Guide to the Helena and Elizabeth Mayer papers,1905-1993.
Mayer, Helena and Elizabeth papers,1905-1993.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Helena and Elizabeth Mayer papers, 1905-1993.
4938
Helena Mayer, 1908-1994.
1.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, diaries, manuscripts, documents, notes, articles, diplomas and certificates, art work, ephemera, postcards, financial material, family records, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal papers of the Mayer sisters Helena and Elizabeth include correspondence, photographs, diaries, manuscripts of novels and short stories, and documents pertaining to their status as students, displaced persons, scholars, and naturalized American citizens. Includes academic reading notes, scholarly articles, diplomas and certificates, art work, ephemera (keepsakes, coins), and postcards, financial material, retirement documents, family records, and miscellaneous other papers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University Library employees, 1955-1971.
Born Hungary, displaced persons after the Second World War. Both Ph.D.s, Rome.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal papers of the Mayer sisters Helena and Elizabeth include correspondence, photographs, diaries, manuscripts of novels and short stories, and documents pertaining to their status as students, displaced persons, scholars, and naturalized American citizens. Includes academic reading notes, scholarly articles, diplomas and certificates, art work, ephemera (keepsakes, coins), and postcards, financial material, retirement documents, family records, and miscellaneous other papers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Mayer, Helena, 1908-1994.; Mayer, Elizabeth, 1906-1991.
Subjects:
Family--Hungary.; Family--United States.; Political refugees--Personal narratives.; Fiction.; Political refugees--Hungary.
Places:
Hungary--Description and travel.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.; Postcards.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Retirement and general financial documents, 1963-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Library and displaced person identification cards, 1931-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Hungarian citizenship papers, school papers and other family documents, 1935-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- E. Mayer, "The Vatican Library," speech (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Art work by E. Mayer (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, on postcards; largely undated, but before WWII (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, fragments, 1955-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Diary; notes on sightseeing in Rome, June 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Diary, 1947-1964, 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Diary, "Ithaca: la città dolore", 1956-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Diary [time of her sister's death], June-Nov. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Diary, June 12, Aug. 21, 1992; Mar. 9, [1993?] (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Recollections, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Tribute to Mother, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Reading notes on Roman History, genealogy and other books (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Reading notes (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Manuscript, "Novellen" (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
- Manuscript (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Manuscript, "Aus dem Nebel," 3 parts (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Manuscript, "Aus dem Nebel, Bk. II, Die Revolution" (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Manuscript (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
- Manuscript, "Die Heilige und ihre Gefangenen" (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Manuscript, "Die vier Ritter," etc. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Manuscript (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Manuscript, "Christmas, 1991," etc. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Manuscript fragments (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Manuscript music, E. Mayer (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Manuscript recipes, E. Mayer (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Photographs, Mayer family, 1905-1914 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Photographs, Mayer father and mother, 1904-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Photographs, Mayer sisters, 1909-1940 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Photographs, E. Mayer, 1907-1935 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Photographs, E. Mayer, 1937-1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Photographs, H. Mayer, 1908-1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Photographs, H. Mayer, 1937-1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Photographs, Mayer family, misc., 1931-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Photographs, Mayer family, Totterer family, n.d.-1934 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Identification cards and admission tickets (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Material on Fairview Heights (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Grade books and published articles, E. Mayer (Box 3)
- Grade books and published articles, H. Mayer (Box 3)
- Coins, pens, postcards, photographs and music (Box 4)
- Oversized diplomas and certificates including Certificates of Naturalization for both sisters (Box 5)